[ Film projector whirring ]
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
♪
[ Dramatic music plays ]
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
♪
[ Dramatic music plays ]
[ Lawn mower whirring ]
[ Birds chirping ]
[ Dramatic music plays ]
Hmm ?
[ Gasps ]
♪
[ Majestic music plays ]
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
♪
[ Dramatic music plays ]
[ Lights buzzing ]
[ Static on TV ]
[ Static intensifies ]
[ Indistinct shouting on TV ]
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
[ Static ]
♪
Mindless violence lit up the sky .
America ... the 1970s .
The energy crisis is real .
♪ I 'm runnin ' away
- A time of unrest and mistrust . - I have never been a quitter .
[ Siren wails ]
- It was a night of terror . - A time of fear and violence .
♪
We are entering a satanic age !
Anyone who can 't see that is blind !
[ Screams ]
Television documents the chaos ,
beams the horror into our living room .
[ Intense electronic rock plays ]
And so it is done .
[ Flames roar ]
But it also offers comfort . [ Up-tempo theme music plays ]
April 4 , 1971 ...
the first episode of UBC 's " Night Owls " goes to air .
The network 's hopes for a late-night hit
are riding on the shoulders of the host ,
a popular Chicago radio announcer .
Good evening , night owls . I 'm your host , Jack Delroy .
And thank you for allowing me into your living rooms
for the first of what I hope will be many , many shows .
[ Chuckles ]
I 'd like to thank everyone who helped bring this dream to life ,
especially my dear mom and dad back in Berwyn , Illinois ,
who I know are sitting in front of their TV set ,
big smiles on their faces ,
watching " The Tonight Show " with Johnny Carson .
[ Rim shot , laughter ]
[ Cheers and applause ]
With its entertaining mix of interviews ,
music , and sketch comedy , " Night Owls " with Jack Delroy
captures the hearts and minds of midnight America .
- [ Up-tempo music plays ] - [ Laughs ]
[ Cheers and applause ]
Well , I am sick of it , Crog ,
stuck in the cave all day , cooking your sabertooth stew .
Oi , fellas , does this sound familiar ?
This is an Amazonian bird-eating spider .
Looks like your furry little friend , uh ,
might have gotten a better offer .
- [ Woman screams ] - Don 't panic . I got it , Jack .
- I got it . Excuse me , sir . - Gus .
Five nights a week ,
Jack helps an anxious nation forget its troubles .
[ Laughs ]
In November 1972 ,
Jack inks a five-year deal with UBC owner Walker Bedford .
Welcome to UBC family , Jack .
What did you have to sacrifice to get here tonight ?
With an Emmy nomination to his name
and growing audience share ,
Jack sights are set on the coveted late-night crown .
♪
By Jack 's side through everything is his wife ,
the beloved stage actress Madeleine Piper .
Despite Jack 's relentless quest to be number one ,
they are considered one of showbiz 's happiest
and most enduring couples .
Madeleine is his muse and his confidante ,
but she is not his only source of support .
[ Soft , dramatic music plays ]
Jack 's association with The Grove ,
a men-only club located in the redwoods of California ,
has been the subject of rumors since his days in radio .
Established in the 1800s
and counting among its members politicians ,
entertainers , and captains of industry ,
The Grove has long portrayed itself
as a harmless summer camp for the rich and powerful .
[ Men howling and trilling ]
But speculation swirls around its taste for arcane ceremony
and its power to make and break careers .
... 8 ... 7 ... 6 ...
Four seasons on , and ratings still fail to match Carson .
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
The nominations mount , but no trophy .
Jack 's reputation as perennial also-ran starts to bite .
He knows that history remembers only kings .
Then , in September 1976 ,
Jack 's world is turned upside-down
when Madeleine , a nonsmoker ,
is diagnosed with terminal lung cancer .
In October , Madeleine makes a special appearance on the show .
[ Breathlessly ] Jack and I first met
when I was doing " Oh ! Calcutta ! " ...
- Oh , God . - ... at the Eden .
My , you should have seen him blush
when he came backstage and [ Gasps ] was
confronted with all those glorious naked bodies .
[ Audience murmurs ] Remember , darling ?
Madeleine , I don 't think we need to talk about ...
See , [ Gasps ] he 's blushing right now .
[ Laughter ] How is a girl
not supposed to fall in love with that ?
[ Audience " Awws " ]
Isn 't she something , ladies and gentlemen ?
- [ Cheers and applause ] - It is the highest-rating
episode in " Night Owls " history ,
but still falls a point short of Carson .
- I love you , Jack . - [ Mouthing words ]
[ Applause ]
Two weeks later , Madeleine is dead .
[ Inhaling deeply ]
[ Camera shutters clicking ]
A grieving Jack shuns the media .
He flees New York , his location unknown .
Just one month later , and to the surprise of many ,
UBC announces his return .
Ladies and gentlemen , Mr. Jack Delroy .
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Soft , dramatic music plays ]
But the gap between Delroy and Carson continues to widen .
Jack and his longtime producer , Leo Fiske ,
go out of their way to court controversy ,
in a bid to improve audience share .
[ Indistinct shouting ]
[ Grunting ]
You used to be the [ bleep ] man , Jack .
What the [ bleep ] happened to you ?
[ Audience murmurs ] Huh ?
We are gonna take a break , and I 'll ...
I 'll be right back . And you will not .
Where the [ bleep ] do you think you 're going ? Huh ?
- Open the [ bleep ] door ! - Ratings are in free fall .
Sponsors are nervous .
Jack 's contract is set to expire .
Everything is on the line when Sweeps Week begins
- on Halloween night , 1977 . - [ Speaking French ]
A desperate Jack plans an episode
he hopes will turn his fortunes around .
Get the audience in , guys . [ Door creak , slam ]
What you are about to see is the recently discovered
master tape of what went to air that night ,
as well as previously unreleased behind-the-scenes footage .
It is the live TV event that shocked a nation ...
" Late Night With the Devil . "
[ Eerie music plays ]
[ Static , beeping ]
[ Electronic hum ]
Tonight 's broadcast is brought to you
by the Cavendish Group of Companies .
Let 's shake on it .
[ Cheers and applause ]
Live from UBC Studios in New York City ,
it 's " Night Owls " with Jack Delroy !
[ Up-tempo theme music plays ]
Joining us on our spooky Halloween special ,
Christou ...
Carmichael Haig ...
Dr. June Ross-Mitchell with the subject of her new book ,
Lilly ...
Miss Cleo James with a bewitching jazz medley ...
plus our annual Halloween costume parade .
But now here 's Mr. Midnight ... Jack Delroy !
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Chuckles ]
Oh , boy . Jack ?
Where the hell is he ?
[ Laughter ]
Uh , Jack , you 're on . [ Audience murmurs ]
- Leo , he 's not , uh ... - Boo !
Aw , Jesus , Mary , and Joseph ! [ Laughter ]
[ Growls ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughter and applause ]
Gus McConnell , ladies and gentlemen .
[ Chuckles ] You .
[ Laughter ]
Oh , good evening , night owls , and thank you for allowing me
into your living rooms once again .
We 've got an incredible show lined up for you tonight
as we celebrate all of the fiendish fun of Halloween .
[ Eerie whistling ] Ew . Oh , hello .
Um , what do you got there , Gus ?
A theremin Jack . It 's a musical instrument .
Oh , that 's not music , Gus .
That is actually the sound you get
when you 're tuning your car radio ,
searching for music . [ Laughter ]
What 's interesting about a theremin , Jack ,
is you play it without touching it .
So , you 're not meant to touch it ?
No , sir . No touching .
Why , Gus , if only you 'd shown the same restraint
at the Melody Burlesque after Friday 's show .
Hmm . [ Laughter and applause ]
Think we should raise the bar in here
a little bit tonight , folks . Um , anybody go
to the Yankees ' parade ? [ Cheers and applause ]
Yeah ! Any Reggie Jackson fans in here ?
[ Cheers and applause ]
Knew she was . Now , there 's a rumor
going around that " Cosmo " magazine
has approached Reggie to be their very own Mr. October .
- [ Audience " Oohs " ] - Ooh .
We can expect Reggie 's impressive homerun spree
to continue well into the offseason .
[ Bat hits ball ] [ Laughter and applause ]
We doing good ? Have one more ?
[ Thud ] Hey ! Whoa !
That one went over the fence .
[ Applause ] Whew ! [ Laughs ]
- I don 't get that joke , Jack . - Oh , well .
I guess we 're gonna have to raise the bar
to Gus 's standards now , folks .
Uh , yeah , so , apparently , President Jimmy Carter ...
Really , Leo ? [ Cheering ]
Oh , you 're ... Oh , well , okay . Easy pickings , I guess .
[ Laughter ] Um ...
so , President Carter held a press conference today
announcing a reorganization of his staff .
When asked if his brother Billy was part of the plans ,
the president said that he 'd offered
Billy a chance to head either the FBI ...
is this true ? or the CIA . Wow .
- That can 't be true . - Apparently , Billy said
he refused to head any agency that he couldn 't spell .
[ Laughter ] [ Rim shot ]
- I get that joke . - You got it ?
- I got it . - Gus got it .
[ Laughter ]
Well , night owls , we 've got a heck of a show
in store for you tonight , and I 'm very excited for you
to see it all unfold before your very eyes .
I really hope you love it . Gosh , I hope you love it .
Please love it , because , well ...
it 's Sweeps Week .
[ Dramatic chords play ]
Oh ! That 's right .
Where is Vincent Price when you need him ?
Boy , I tell you what .
Now , Sweeps Week , as we all know ,
is the all-important national ratings period .
But , hey , do I look nervous to you , Gus ?
You better believe it , Jack . [ Laughter ]
We all know how important it is to keep our sponsors
and affiliates happy . But in my humble opinion ,
there is only one person who really matters
in this whole darn crazy business .
- Well , thank you Jack . - And that is you , our viewer .
[ Laughter ]
You have stood by me through thick and thin ,
good times and bad . Especially the bad .
It was your support that [ Sighs ] brought me back
into this very studio a year ago ,
when I could have easily thrown in the towel ,
when many suggested
that I should have thrown in the towel .
This show is ... and it always has been ... for you .
- Love you , Jack ! - And [ Sighs ] ...
[ Audience " Awws " ] [ Sighs ]
Leo , can we please get that woman a Nielsen viewing diary ?
Come on . [ Laughter ]
Thank you all .
What do you say , night owls ? On with the show , huh ?
Yeah !
- [ Cheers and applause ] - Alright
Interest in the occult has seen a major revival in recent years .
This is true . You open any newspaper today ,
you 're gonna see hundreds of ads for psychics
or fortune tellers , exorcists , even .
Whoa ! [ Audience " Whoas " ]
Now , as you know , here on " Night Owls , "
we think it 's very important to keep an open mind .
Our first guest tonight ...
I am so excited about this young man ...
is a shining light in this movement .
Some call him a medium ; others , a spiritualist .
Some have even called him a miracle worker .
We know him by one name , and , well ,
that 's probably because one name is all he seems to have .
Ladies and gentlemen , please help me welcome
the mysterious , the mononymous Christou .
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Indian music plays ]
♪
[ Cheers and applause ]
Thank you for being here .
So , it is just Christou , is that right ?
[ Middle Eastern accent ] Sí , that is correct .
Thank you for inviting me onto your program .
Oh , please , thank you for taking time
out of your busy touring schedule .
You are a hot ticket these days . I tell you what .
- It is my pleasure . - Now , as I understand it ,
a night like tonight , a spooky night like Halloween ,
holds a special significance for someone in your profession .
That is correct . All Hallows Eve is a time
to break open the doors to the underworld .
It is the last chance for the spirits of the recently deceased
to attend to any unfinished business .
- Hmm . - Ooh .
So that explains the significance , then ,
- of the Halloween masks . - Sí , yes .
We use them to hide from the angry spirits .
Oh . I 'm so curious .
Do you hear these voices of the dead all the time ?
The energy is ever-present , sí .
And then I guess the burning question is ,
how the hell do you get any sleep ?
[ Laughter ] I mean , right ?
Just think of my mind like the ham radio ,
picking up frequencies in the airwaves .
When I no longer want to listen , I simply switch it off .
Just like that ? Wow .
Okay , well , then I think it is time , ladies and gentlemen ,
that we fire up those frequencies .
The energy in here is very strong .
Thank you , Phil . The floor is yours , sir .
Ladies and gentlemen , Christou . [ Cheers and applause ]
[ Inhales deeply ]
[ Gasps ]
I 'm already receiving some signals here .
[ Breathing unevenly ]
[ Grunts ]
The letter " P , " I 'm hearing .
[ Breathing unevenly ]
Peter . [ Audience murmurs ]
Pete .
No , wait . It 's clearer now .
Peterson . I 'm hearing the name Peterson .
- Peterman ? - What ? I 'm sorry .
Sir , you 're up there . Yeah . Okay , okay , sir. sir .
You can stand up back there . Thank you .
- Hi , Mr. Peterson . - Uh , no .
Uh , my wife 's maiden name was Peterman .
Yes , that is it ... Peterman . She 's in the room with us now .
She is ?
Your wife has crossed over , sí ?
You could say that .
She ran off with my neighbor five years ago .
[ Laughter ]
- Sorry to hear that . - Oh , don 't be .
My golf game 's never been better .
[ Laughter ]
No , but there is a ...
Now I 'm hearing the name Elizabeth .
No , her name was Helen .
- There was no Beth or Betty ? - Correct .
- There was a Betty . - No . You 're correct .
There was no Beth or Betty . [ Laughter ]
- A name starting with " B. " - Oh , my name 's Barry .
- That 's not it . - No , it has been for 42 years .
[ Laughter ]
Gone . The spirit has passed . I 'm sorry .
Sometimes the signal gets scrambled .
Studio lights , cameras . I am only a messenger .
I concentrate .
Barry , have a seat . Thank you so much .
- Thank you . - And you , sir ?
Looks like you went on a shopping spree with Gus
down at , uh , Barney 's Discount Costume Warehouse , huh ?
[ Laughter ] Got quite a steal on that , huh ?
Don 't be upset . I 'm just ribbing you .
- [ Laughter ] - Oh , Jack .
I 'm receiving something . [ Exhales sharply ]
I 'm getting a ... Oh , yes , this intrigues .
[ Breathing heavily ]
- Good evening , ladies . - Good evening . [ Chuckles ]
Evening , evening .
- [ Chuckles ] - Who is Edward ?
Eddie ? He was a son or brother for one of you , sí ?
Edmond was my little brother .
- And you were the mother , sí ? - Sí . I mean , yes .
[ Laughter ]
Deduction , Jack , not psychic powers .
I am still impressed . Wow . [ Laughter ]
Something bad happened to Edmond .
It 's ... hard to talk about it ?
Yes .
- Many questions remain . - Well , h-he ...
It may be that Edmond took his own life ?
- Quite recently , too . - Five years ago .
I know , but it feels like only yesterday .
Such a terrible tragedy .
There was much confusion why he did this , no ?
Terrible sadness and confusion . This is so .
- There was no note . Nothing . - No .
He was such a happy boy .
None of us knew he was in so much pain .
[ Audience murmurs ]
Eddie wants you to know that he is at peace now .
He 's sorry for the suffering he has caused .
He communicates this to you . His heart is full of love .
[ Chuckles ]
Now I 'm hitting the word " papa . "
Well , Dad was always Dad . We never ...
No , wait . Um ...
[ Sniffles ]
When Edmond was little , he had a teddy named Papa .
- This is true . - Oh , my God . I remember .
[ Sniffles ] I kept all his things .
Can you please tell him that Papa is safe ?
[ Sniffling ]
I do not need to tell him this .
He already knows . [ Audience " Awws " ]
Thank you . You are both so beautiful .
Bless you . Bless you all !
- [ Cheers and applause ] - Wow !
Wow ! What a ... What a gift .
Thank you . Christou ! Wow !
[ Chuckles ]
Now these tour dates
should be showing up on your screens momentarily .
We 're gonna have to take a quick break , folks .
When we come back , though , one of the old friends
- of our show who always ... - [ Groaning loudly ]
- [ Screams ] - Christou ?
[ Breathing heavily ] [ Audience murmurs ]
Something very intense here . [ Gasps ]
Perhaps ... Are we getting another message from Edmond ?
No , no . This is ...
[ Screams ] [ Audience gasps ]
I 'm getting the name ... Minnie .
Does anyone here know a Minnie ? Please accept .
Does this name mean anything to anyone in the studio ?
No ? Um , perhaps a name that sounds like Minnie .
Maybe it 's like a Millie or a Mandy .
- I had a Great-Aunt Molly . - It 's Minnie !
[ Audience gasps ] Please ! Who will accept ?
[ Grunts ] So much sadness .
I see [ Gasps ] a wedding ring .
An unmarried man with a wedding ring .
The spirit needs to talk to you . Who are you ? !
[ Electricity crackles ] [ Audience screaming ]
It 's okay , folks , it 's just our old par cans acting up .
[ Gasping ] [ Audience murmurs ]
[ Gasping ]
Gone . S-She 's gone .
S-S-She 's gone .
[ Gasping ]
- Leo ? - [ Breathing heavily ]
We 're gonna take a quick break ,
and we 're gonna be right back after these messages .
[ Up-tempo theme music plays ]
[ Cheers and applause ]
♪
[ Music stops ]
And we 're clear . [ Bell rings ]
Gus to wardrobe .
Hey , Mr. Christou , that was fantastic .
You are truly blessed . Jack , can we talk ?
- Not right now , Gus . - It 's just backstage .
They 're saying you and Leo have got something cooked up
- when that girl comes on . - As far as I know ,
- we 're sticking to the rundown . - Right , right .
It 's just , I saw restraints , Jack , and ... and knives .
I 've got to be honest with you .
We 're a little spooked back there .
What the hell are you still doing here ?
- Get to wardrobe , pronto . - Yes , sir . Yes , sir .
- Fantastic segment , fellas . - Mr. Christou ,
you look like you might need a bourbon .
- Just some water , please . - In this place ?
- I 'll see what I can do . - Some water for Mr. Christou .
Are you happy to stay with us a little longer ?
- I really should be ... - That 's the spirit .
I can 't wait to catch your act , by the way .
Here , you 've got some blood under your nose .
- Jack , mind if we ... - Thank you .
Jesus Christ .
The charlatan really went all-out there .
Oh , boy . That bit with the lights was your idea , wasn 't it ?
If you liked it , yeah , I 'll take full credit .
- Mm-hmm . - What did you think
about our friend Barry ?
[ Indistinct conversations ]
- You okay , buddy ? - Yeah . Just that last ...
Look , whatever happened was great television .
Don 't let it rattle you . Okay , some orders of business .
We 're running long , late to break .
Okay , but we 're not bumping Cleo again .
Well , we 'll try to make up some time .
Oh , don 't look now , but Cavendish 's new
vice president of marketing and his wife
are sitting in the front row with the head of airtime .
You 're looking directly at them . I don 't understand that .
Hey , they want to talk to you . They want to meet you .
No , I don 't have time to play kiss-ass right now .
In case you hadn 't noticed , I 'm trying to host
a nationally syndicated talk show .
And I 'm trying to help you keep it on the air .
- McConnell ? - Okay .
- Where 's McConnell ? - Next break .
- Mm . - Okay ?
How 's June ? Did they land ? Is she okay ?
- She 's fine . Just fine . - Great . The girl ?
Jack , will you please relax ?
Everything 's going very , very well .
Phil , what the hell 's going on with those lights ?
- We 're working on it . - 30 seconds , people !
- Hey . - Nothing 's been fixed
- since 1956 . - Hey , great show so far .
- Sammy , how are you ? - Good . How are you ?
I 'm okay . How 's my hair looking ?
- Alright . You look great . - Good .
- Bats in the cave ? - You 're all clear .
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
- Thank you . - Hey , Jack , which card ?
- Hey . - Is this necessary ?
You got a little bit of a sweat going on , honey .
Please , stop !
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Fine . Suit yourself .
Hey . Hmm ?
Fear not , friends , your humble sidekick has returned .
- [ Laughter ] - Stand by everyone .
- Staging , the door . - Too kind .
Haig 's on next . Pay him no mind .
He 's all wax , no wick . Okay ?
And we 're back in 5 ... 4 ... [ Door closes ]
[ Coughs ] [ Film projector whirring ]
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
[ Bat squeaking ]
♪
Thank you . Welcome back to our Halloween special , folks .
For those of you just tuning in ,
Mr. Christou here wowed us before the break
with a demonstration of his mediumistic powers .
It was really something . Am I right ?
- [ Cheers and applause ] - [ Coughs ]
Amazing . Our next guest
is someone equally renowned in his own field .
Once known to us all as Carmichael the Conjurer .
You remember him ? Yeah ? Well , he hung up the wand
several years ago to become
one of the leading voices of the skeptics movement .
Ladies and gentlemen , make welcome ,
if you dare , Mr. Carmichael Haig .
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
♪
- So good to see you again , Car . - [ Coughs ]
It 's wonderful to be here , Jack .
- Mind if I smoke ? - [ Coughs ]
Please be my guest .
Oh , boy , that was good . [ Audience murmurs ]
Mmm .
[ Audience murmurs ]
Wow .
[ Audience murmurs ] He 's still got it .
[ Fanfare ] Ladies and gentlemen .
Holy smoke . [ Audience groans ]
Come ... Come on . [ Applause ]
I 'm right here . Car ...
we all know you from the Vegas shows ,
- the TV specials . - [ Coughs ]
Your group-hypnosis routine was the first of its kind .
Absolutely boggled my mind when I saw it .
Many regarded you as the best in the biz .
And I know my saying that won 't embarrass you .
Correct . On all counts . Continue , dear friend .
- [ Laughter ] - But in recent years ,
it seems you 've turned your attention
to something a little more , shall we say , philanthropic ?
- You mean IFSIP ? - IFSIP .
Now , IFSIP , for those of you not in the know , is an acronym .
It stands for ... let me get this right here ...
the International Federation
of Scientific Investigation into the Paranormal .
Ooh . It 's a lot of words . We 've got some pictures up
right here . Take a look .
Photogenic lot , aren 't we ?
Yes , it is our mission to test these claims
and determine what is trickery
and what may , in fact , be genuine psi phenomena .
Oh , that 's me about to embark on a little ghost hunt
in Amityville . [ Audience " Oohs " ]
My dear friends Ed and Lorraine Warren
declined the invitation to join me .
Easily spooked . [ Laughter ]
Car , be honest with me . What is the harm
for those of us who just want to believe in something mysterious ,
something bigger than ourselves , hmm ?
Jack , I 'm the first to admit
that the world would be a more interesting place
if , uh ... if people could magically bend spoons
or divine water with a stick or ...
talk to the dead . [ Audience groans ]
But until I am presented with irrefutable proof ...
- [ Coughing ] - I will continue to expose
these men and women for the swindlers they are .
Still carry that check with you , Car ?
Oh , yes .
We offer a not-insubstantial reward
for anyone whose claims can be verified .
Get a shot on this ?
Camera 1.100 grand . [ Audience murmurs ]
How many have taken up the challenge ?
- [ Coughs ] - Oh , dozens .
And how many checks have you signed ?
Yet to sacrifice a nickel , Jack .
Tonight might be the night , though , folks .
Right ? [ Cheers and applause ]
I do not need this man 's money .
No , I imagine you don 't . Not when there are so many naive
but well-meaning people prepared to hand over their hard-earned .
- [ Coughing deeper ] - You okay ?
Oh . Do you need a drink of water ?
- You okay ? - [ Coughing ]
[ Gulping ]
[ Coughs ] I 'm alright , thank you .
Hey , um ...
Now , Car , explain to us Mr. Christou 's readings , then ,
- before we went to break . - What I saw was an admittedly
accomplished performer digging from a bag of tricks
that goes back to biblical times .
By my count , Christou flopped no less than five times
before he hit on the tenuous Peterson connection .
- It was Peterman . - [ Chuckles ]
He ... He 's flawless in hindsight .
Okay , Car , but I observed nothing untoward
when Mr. Christou appeared to connect
these two ladies with their deceased son .
We all saw that , everyone here , right ?
To which I would say ,
even a broken clock is right twice a day .
False lies ! [ Audience boos ]
You no more have the power of divination
- than I resemble Burt Reynolds . - [ Laughs ]
You , sir , like me , are a liar , a cheat , a charlatan ,
and a fake . The difference being ,
I 'm honest about it . [ Audience boos ]
Come on . [ Audience shouting ]
Oh ! Okay .
A flair for the theatrical doesn 't go astray .
Christou , wait , I still have to ask you something .
- Please . - Christou .
We have not yet discussed the last reading .
Yet another cold trail . Minnie , Molly , Mandy , anyone ?
Put a sock in it , will you , Car ?
Enough . [ Sighs ]
Funny as it may seem ...
I actually believe that that last reading
may have been meant for me .
[ Audience murmurs ]
Yes ?
Minnie ... Who ... Who 's Minnie ?
Minnie is the private nickname
for ...
Madeleine , my wife . [ Audience murmurs ]
- Hmm . - Your wife ?
Yes . S-She crossed over , didn 't she ?
[ Groans ]
An unmarried man wearing a wedding ring ?
[ Audience murmurs ] I think you meant this .
Jack , please .
Half the people in this room are wearing one .
- Okay . - And Madeleine 's death
was hardly a secret . This is what I 'm talking about .
It is a statistical certainty
that some fool will take the bait .
Don 't be that fool .
- What are you up to , Car ? - Let 's see if the mad monk
really can conjure up the spirit of your dead wife
live on air .
Half a $ 1 million should be incentive enough .
[ Thud ] No ?
[ Audience gasps , Christou groans ]
Christou . [ Stomach growling ]
Buddy ? [ Christou grunts ]
[ Christou vomits , audience screams ]
- God damn it , man ! - [ Gasps ]
Go to a commercial ! Go to a goddamn commercial !
[ Vomits ]
- [ Bell rings ] - Clear !
- It 's okay . - Can we get some help here ?
It 's gonna be okay . You 're just overtired , baby .
No ! Something 's not right !
We need a doctor !
Get him to his dressing room now .
And someone just clean up all this mess .
The Surgeon General strongly advises
taking Pepto Bismol before speaking with the dead .
Uh , so , is anyone here from out of town ?
This was a gift from Charles Laughton ,
- I 'll have you know . - [ Sighs ]
You , you , you . [ Snaps fingers ]
Fetch the burgundy blazer from my portmanteau , will you ?
Christ , it must have been a seizure or something .
You play the aw-shucks Midwesterner so well , Jack .
That bit about Madeleine and your secret nickname ?
Very impressive .
What are you talking about ? There are only three ways
he could have known about that .
One , he 's actually psychic ,
which we both know is impossible .
Two , he got lucky . Possible , but highly improbable .
Or three ...
You think that I told him ?
I wouldn 't blame you if you did .
A little on-air drama can 't be bad for ratings , right ?
- Right , right . - I do read the trades , Jack .
I 'd have thought your high-powered friends
at The Grove could pull a few strings .
I think you overestimate their influence .
You must invite me along one of these days .
I 'd love to know if the rumors are true ...
the secret handshakes , the orgies ,
the arcane ceremonies . But mostly the orgies .
Jack , rundown briefing .
Give me an audience with the Grand Poobah , Jack .
[ Sighs ] I 'll fit right in .
Good man , Sticks .
I told you not to leave me alone with that asshole .
What am I ... your mother ? The ambulance is coming .
You can talk to Cavendish in the next break .
Extenuating circumstances .
- Any word from Bedford yet ? - Mnh-mnh .
The switchboard lit up like a Rosenberg , though .
- People are upset ? Offended ? - Angry , confused .
None of which is terrible news , of course . That 's great .
- Mr. Fiske . - No , no , no , no , no .
This comes out in the next break .
Check your rundown . [ Bell rings ]
Staging , the door .
Shit . Back to the wings . Oh !
I 'm not picking up anything down here , Steve .
You picking up anything weird , Lou ?
- We 're on in five ... - Coming through .
... four ...
Oh . Not my chair .
[ Up-tempo music plays , cheers and applause ]
♪
[ Music ends ]
Thank you .
And thank you to everyone who 's been calling in
to check on Mr. Christou .
Don 't be alarmed , folks .
He is receiving medical attention backstage as we speak .
They needn 't bother .
The man is perfectly fine , I assure you .
Well ... your dry cleaner may disagree , Car .
[ Laughter ]
Well , that 's just an old vaudeville routine .
Spouting , they call it . Controlled regurgitation .
Anyway , I certainly hope you 're gonna keep
that check handy .
- The check ... - Your breast pocket .
Hmm ? [ Laughs ]
[ Audience " ohhs " ] Silky as ever , Car .
He got you , Jack . [ Laughter ]
My sixth sense
is telling me we may just see this check again
before the night is through .
I very much doubt that .
Wait until you meet our next guests .
[ Unenthusiastically ] Giddy with excitement , Jack .
You should be . [ Laughter ]
Now , about a ... [ Siren wailing ]
[ Audience whispering indistinctly ]
About a month ago ,
a manuscript happened to cross my desk that , well ...
I haven 't been able to stop thinking about , quite frankly .
The book
" Conversations with the Devil "
by Dr. June Ross-Mitchell ... [ Audience " ohhs " ]
... hits shelves this week , and it is certain
to challenge more than a few skeptics out there .
Now , before I bring on the doctor
and the young subject of the book ,
I wanted to share with you all a clip produced
by June 's psi-research center .
Hopefully catch us all up to speed .
But please be warned , anyone
with young children in the room ...
What you 're about to see is profoundly disturbing
and shocking .
Can we roll the tape , please ?
[ Ominous music plays ]
A seemingly ordinary house on an ordinary street .
[ Bell ringing ] Only this is the headquarters
of the infamous First Church of Abraxas .
I command thee to come forth
and bestow these blessings of hell upon us .
Hail , Abraxas !
- Hail , Abraxas ! - Hail , Abraxas !
The church 's founder and leader ,
the enigmatic Szandor D 'Abo .
Abraxas shows us
there is no good , no evil ,
no redemption .
Only what we desire and how we obtain it .
You make it sound very easy , Monsieur D 'Abo .
Make no mistake ... The master demands sacrifice .
D 'Abo 's activities come to the attention of the FBI ,
who suspect the cult of kidnapping and firearm offenses .
But even more alarming are the stories of children
being bred for human sacrifice .
... and the spilling of blood .
Come forth . Open the gates of hell .
D 'Abo claims that anyone who witnesses these dreadful rituals
will fall under the spell of the demon Abraxas ,
and so perform his earthly bidding .
And so it is done !
- [ Sirens wailing ] - Events take a tragic turn
in August ' 74 ... [ Gunshots ]
... when federal agencies lay siege to the house .
Shots have been fired . [ Explosion ]
After a tense three-day standoff ,
D 'Abo commands his followers to douse the premises
and themselves in gasoline .
But remarkably , among the smoldering ruins ,
a terrified 10-year-old girl is discovered .
She goes only by the name of Lilly .
Her memories of her time in the house ...
fractured and incomplete .
Was her survival part of D 'Abo 's wicked master plan ,
or was she simply the lucky one ?
At a loss to explain Lilly 's strange behavior ,
the FBI contacts my psi research center .
Lilly and I make an immediate connection .
Important breakthroughs follow ,
but there is still much work to be done .
It 's 2 : 30 p.m. , July 10 , 1976 .
This is a recording of our first session .
[ Lilly breathing heavily ]
Okay . [ Thud ]
It seems we 've made contact .
Who am I speaking to now ?
Is this the demon known as ...
[ Lilly screaming ] Oh , my God !
Hold her tight ! [ Glass shatters ]
Help ! We need some help in here !
[ Lilly screaming ]
[ Audience gasping ]
Wow .
Ladies and gentlemen , please welcome
Dr. June Ross-Mitchell and Lilly .
[ Mid-tempo music plays , cheers and applause ]
♪
Oh . You can come out .
Hi . [ Audience " awws " ]
Lilly . [ Cheers and applause ]
June .
♪
How are ya ?
Whoa ! [ Laughter ]
Good to meet ya .
So good to see you again , June .
- You too , Jack . - And , Lilly [ Sighs ]
so pleased that you could join us today .
Thank you , Mr. Delroy .
I 'm so glad you could join us , too .
[ Light laughter , Jack chuckles ]
Now , Lilly , you don 't have to look at the camera .
You can actually talk directly to me .
Oh , I 'm sorry .
Don 't be silly .
I want to start with a tough question , if that 's okay .
I 'd like to know ...
Have you ever watched my show before ?
[ Laughter ]
No . I 'm normally in bed by now .
But I know who you are , Mr. Delroy .
Oh , please . You can call me Jack .
June says you 're very handsome , Jack .
[ Audience " oohs " ]
[ June chuckles nervously ]
You 're the man whose wife died of cancer .
Lilly , I don 't think Jack wants to ...
I was very sad when I heard about that .
I know what it 's like to lose people who are close to you .
It 's lonely at first , but you 'll get through .
Such wise words from one so young , huh ?
Lilly has been through more in her 13 years
than most adults go through in a lifetime .
And you needn 't worry about your TV show .
I think you 're gonna be very famous soon .
Why , thank you for the reassurance .
I was beginning to wonder , Gus .
- [ Laughter ] - Me too . [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs ] You 're welcome .
Okay , well , we 're gonna take a break .
Um , but on the other side ...
yes , the other side ...
we 're going to spend some time
getting to know these two extraordinary ladies .
[ Mid-tempo music plays , cheers and applause ]
- Okay . That was great . - Quite a show .
I was afraid you weren 't gonna make it .
I 'm sorry .
♪
[ Music ends ]
And we 're clear . [ Bell rings ]
Great . That was great , ladies .
Lilly , you are adorable .
Thank you , Jack .
And which camera do I look at now ?
Um , well , we 're off air , so none .
Time to make ourselves pretty again .
Hey , Jack .
Don 't I already look pretty , Jack ?
You 're good .
Sure , you do .
Hi ! I 'm Lilly !
- Jack , we need to talk . - Let me take that
- for you , ma 'am . - Thank you .
- Wow . Weird kid . - She was looking
right down that camera . [ Jack sighs ]
That was great . You ready ?
- [ Mid-tempo music plays ] - This is so much fun .
Welcome to the dream factory , kid .
I really don 't think it 's a good idea , Jack .
She 's becoming more unpredictable .
See , unpredictable ... That 's a good thing .
That 's why we still do live TV .
I mean , it 's what 's gonna help sell your book .
- This isn 't about the book . - Isn 't it ?
Yesterday she went into one of her fugue states ,
and she , uh ...
she started saying your name .
She 's excited about being on the show .
No , it was as if she was recalling something .
It was hard to make sense of it , but it was strange even for her .
Look , you are ready for this .
You told me that you 're ready for it . You know you did .
Yes . Well , there may have been a few lapses of judgment
on my part that ...
This is your time . You 've done the work .
You 're not gonna back out right now .
Yeah , I admit you made a convincing case .
But my first responsibility is to Lilly .
And I 'm telling you , it 's too risky .
- [ Footsteps approaching ] - No , I ...
I should get back to her . [ Leo clears throat ]
She 's not getting cold feet , is she ?
- She 's fine . She is fine . - [ Sighs ]
I 'm handling it !
- Hey , Jack . - Hey .
Okay , so just got a call from Sinai .
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Yeah , I know , I know , I know .
- Christou is dead . - What ?
He had some kind of hemorrhage in the ambulance .
- Holy shit . - I know .
No . No , no , no .
I thought that that was all part of his act .
The ... What did Haig call it ? Spouting ?
Well , apparently he was spouting from , well , everywhere .
The paramedics couldn 't get it under control .
- Jesus Christ ! - I know . I know , I know , I know .
- I know , I know , I know . - Listen to me .
Nobody can find out about this , especially not Gus .
I 'll do the best that I can , gut you know how quickly
- word spreads around here . - Staging ,
where 's my sacrificial dagger ?
We 're on 60 second .
Hey , hey , Phil . Has the rundown changed ?
Staging 's saying something about a new bit in seg five ,
- and I don 't see it on my ... - Wait . Shh , shh , shh .
Look , I 'm telling you , Steve , whatever it is ,
we 're not seeing it on the monitor down here .
- Hey , Phil . - Come on , guys !
You just keep switching cameras ,
and I 'll make sure everybody gets their cues , okay ?
- Phil ! Phil ! - Stand by , everyone .
- Phil ! - Then there was a questionnaire
you had to complete before coming in , you say ?
Yeah , that 's right .
Oh , and there was a lady in the lobby
who asked a bunch of questions , too .
Oh , yeah . It was the same woman
who came out and helped Mr. Christou when he ...
Oh , yes , I know . Most disturbing , wasn 't it ?
- Thank you , ladies . - All sorts of stuff lately .
- Yeah . - No wonder we ...
Thank you .
Phil said we 're coming back .
Is everything okay , Jack ?
Yeah . Everything is fine , sweetie .
- 10 seconds ! - Where the hell is Haig ?
- [ Bell rings ] - And we 're back in five ...
four ...
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Eerie music plays ]
♪
[ Music ends ]
And welcome back to our very special
Halloween edition of " Night Owls . "
Now , ladies , there is so much
that I 'd like to discuss with you both ,
but I want to start with you , June .
Now , you call yourself a parapsychologist .
- What exactly does that ... - I call myself one
because that 's what I am , Jack .
It so happens I have a PhD in the subject .
From the University of Hogwash , if I 'm not mistaken .
The Stanford Research Institute , actually .
The difference being ? [ Audience " ohhs " ]
Is it really worth us continuing if this man
is going to interrupt every time you ask a question ?
Car , please behave . [ Scattered applause ]
As I was going to say ,
we parapsychologists believe there are certain phenomena ,
psi phenomena ,
that traditional science is ill-equipped to understand .
Telepathy , for example . Telekinesis ,
- apparitional anomalies . - Demonic possession .
" Psychic infestation " is the term we prefer , but yes .
And it 's your belief
that Lilly here presents just such a case .
For the past three years ,
I 've been combining age regression therapy
with a growing understanding of ancient Satanic rituals
to piece together the details of Lilly 's life
and to grasp the nature of the demon that lurks within her .
This is the demon Abraxas
that the charming Mr. D 'Abo spoke of in your clips ?
No , I believe it 's more likely one of the minor deities
said to serve Abraxas .
These entities thrive on our confusion .
And our stupidity .
[ Audience groans ]
Look , I understand that some of this
might seem to stretch credulity ,
but , remember , big , new scientific ideas
are always greeted with some resistance .
It 's only the most close-minded that greet them with ridicule .
[ Cheers and applause ]
Incidentally , we have some pieces here
from your private collection .
- [ June clears throat ] - Whew !
Okay , well , girl 's got to have a hobby , huh ?
[ Laughter ]
That dagger was recovered from the remains
of the D 'Abo house . We believe it was used in many
of the church 's sacrificial ceremonies .
No ! [ Audience gasps ]
- Oh , God ! - No ! Don 't do it !
- I can 't stop it ! - Stop !
Turn off your TV sets before Abraxas claims your souls !
Car ?
[ Chuckles ] You truly are a suggestible lot .
- Handy to know . - Mr. Haig ,
we haven 't come on here for your amusement .
Don 't be silly , my dear .
If we accept the Gnostic interpretation ,
Abraxas is the consummate showman . He craves an audience .
After all , his name is the source
of the magician 's favorite incantation .
Abracadabra .
Clever girl .
Now , Lilly , I understand that you have a name
for this thing that lives inside of you .
Mm-hmm .
I call him Mr. Wriggles .
And why do you call him that ?
[ Sighs ]
He kind of wriggles his way inside my head ,
and then he wriggles his way out .
But with June 's help , you are able to control him .
June says that everyone has a demon inside them .
But we can 't always control them , can we ?
[ Eerie music plays ]
Gus . Your timing is ...
I got it , Jack .
It 's just a matter of ...
[ Electricity crackling ]
Ooh !
- [ Electricity crackling ] - Gus !
Is there off switch for that thing ?
How the hell should I know ? !
[ Music continues , feedback whining ]
[ Rumbling ]
[ Table rattling ]
[ Glass shattering ]
♪
[ Audience screaming ]
[ Static hissing ]
[ Music stops ]
It was feeding back through your P.A. system .
- No . - It 's the same physics
as when a soprano hits " G " over high " C. "
Poof !
Okay , Car , but come on . That was ...
He 's wrong , you know ?
- It was Mr. Wriggles . - Mr. Wriggles ? !
- He did it . - [ Sighs ]
If you insist , little one .
Why must you be so condescending , Mr. Haig ?
- [ Audience murmuring ] - Lilly , do you mean
that Mr. Wriggles is here in the studio with us right now ?
Mm-hmm .
Would it be okay if we invited him on the show ?
Jack , I thought I made it clear ...
- I think so . - No , I can 't allow that .
A summoning requires a carefully controlled environment .
The lights , cameras , audience ...
Conditions here are hardly conducive .
A TV studio 's a controlled enough environment for my money .
Half a million bucks , to be precise .
Can we ? June , please !
- Yeah ! - We want to see !
- Come on , June . - Come on , June .
- We want to see . - Do it !
Come on !
[ June scoffs lightly ]
- We want to see ! - Show us , June .
Come on , June !
The people have spoken .
If I 'm able to conduct the session
with the full cooperation of your crew , your audience ,
and your guests ,
then perhaps we can attempt a brief demonstration .
- Yeah ! - Yes , of course .
[ Applause ]
This is great news . It 's great news .
Ladies and gentlemen , please stay tuned
for a live television first
as we attempt to commune with the devil .
But not before a word from our sponsors .
[ Up-tempo music plays , cheers and applause ]
♪
[ Music ends ]
Clear ! [ Bell rings ]
Step lively , people . We have two minutes
to prep the main stage , checks on June and Lilly .
You bastard . You ambushed me .
You didn 't require too much convincing , dearie .
- Bread and circuses . - You shut up .
This is your chance to prove people like him wrong .
This is your moment , June .
Did you hear anything I said back there ?
You know , for a talk show host , you 're a terrible listener .
Is somebody gonna clean up the glass ?
Lilly 's okay with it . Aren 't you , sweetheart ?
- Sure , Jack . - Can I get you two ladies
to follow me downstage , please ?
Mm-hmm . Yeah .
- Jack , can I get a minute ? - Can it wait ?
No , sir . It cannot .
Excuse me , uh , Phil .
There are some restraints backstage .
- Would you mind ? - Sure .
I hope you know what you 're doing , lady .
We know what we 're doing , Sammy . Don 't we , June ?
Jerry , you got the new lighting cues ?
[ Sighs ] What ?
You 're meddling with things you don 't understand .
Okay . If we ...
manage to conjure Satan ,
I give you express permission to go right for that exit .
Okay ? If Earth swallows us whole , I apologize in advance .
- Okay ? - What has gotten into you ?
Half an hour ago , you thought
Madeleine was trying to reach out to you from the grave .
- And now ... - Now ... Now , buddy ,
all I 'm trying to do is save our fucking show . Okay ?
So enough with the sanctimonious crap .
I know about Christou .
It 's that Mr. Wriggles , isn 't it ?
He 's behind this whole thing .
Who else knows about Christou ?
Crew 's scared , Jack . I 'm scared .
Okay ? Some of us are talking about jumping ship .
No one 's going anywhere , God damn it .
And you need to keep this fire-and-brimstone bullshit
to yourself . Please , Gus ?
- Okay ? - You are not a bad man , Jack .
You 're not . And I am begging you
to stop this before something terrible happens .
Jack , you 're gonna intro the girls downstage .
Mm .
Is there a problem here ?
Stand by , everybody .
There 's no problem .
[ Bell rings ]
We are back in five ...
four ...
Welcome back , everyone .
Without further ado , Dr. June Ross-Mitchell
will commence the demonstration .
And might I say to you both , Godspeed ?
Thank you , Jack .
Now , if the entity is present tonight ,
it may manifest itself in any number of ways ,
but its entry into our world is only possible through Lilly .
I merely provide the key that unlocks the door .
Whatever you might see or hear , I ask you all to remain calm .
It 's vital that Lilly 's focus remains with me .
[ Lilly chuckles ]
Let us begin . [ Breathes deeply ]
Lilly , to me .
Close your eyes , Lilly .
[ Breathes deeply ]
That 's it .
And let yourself sleep .
[ Breathes deeply ]
Relax .
Lilly , can you hear me ?
Lilly ?
May I speak to the one you know as Mr. Wriggles ?
[ Breathes deeply ]
If Mr. Wrig ...
[ Chair thuds ]
[ Audience gasping ] Quiet .
May I ask who is present now ?
[ Lilly groans , audience gasps ] Shh !
[ Lilly straining , chair thudding ]
Please let yourself be known .
[ Lilly laughing mockingly ]
Speak .
[ Demonic voice ] You know who I am , Doctor .
[ Cracking ]
[ Audience gasps , screams ]
Please .
- Is that the devil ? - I 'm so scared .
Is she okay ?
[ Audience murmuring ]
[ Cracking ]
[ Audience gasps ]
Who are these people ?
[ Cracking ]
What is this ?
[ Audience gasping , chair thudding ]
- Where am I ? ! - There is no need to be alarmed .
What have you done to me , Doctor ?
We mean you no harm .
We 've brought you into this realm to better understand
your purpose .
My purpose ?
He 's here , isn 't he ?
Good to see you again , Jack .
Nah . Sorry .
I don 't believe we 've been acquainted .
Don 't be a fool . We go way back .
We met amongst the tall trees .
- Remember ? - Lilly , return to me .
Oh , Juney , Juney , Juney , Juney !
Be careful now .
You know what happened to his last whore .
She died . She died an ugly , ugly death .
Lilly , come back to me ... now !
And the worms finished off with Minnie a long time ago ,
didn 't they , Jack ?
So now you can screw up whoever you want , hmm ? Like Dr. June .
Dr. June thinks you 're very handsome , Jack .
Dr. June thinks you 're very , very handsome .
That 's enough ! Lilly , I need you to come back to me now !
[ Singsongy voice ] Jack and June went up the hill
to fuck each other 's brains out . [ Audience gasps ]
Jack and Jill went up the hill to [ bleep ] each other 's ...
That 's enough ! [ Audience gasps ]
[ Lilly crying ]
Lilly ?
Lilly , sweetheart ? [ Lilly sniffles ]
[ Normal voice ] Why would you hurt me like that , June ?
You know I can 't help it .
I know . I never ...
[ Screeches ] [ Audience gasps , screams ]
No , Jack ! Stay where you are .
[ Cracking ]
[ Indistinct shouting ]
Vade retro Satana .
- Sunt mala quae libas . - [ Laughs ]
Vade retro Satana . Sunt mala quae libas .
[ Laughing ]
You were cursed by Anum and Antum , Lahmum and Du-rum ,
[ Demonic voice ] The Underworld
and those who lie in it ,
that you shall not seize her ,
- and you shall not return . - And you shall not return !
[ Cracking ]
How could you let it happen , Jack ?
How could you let it happen ?
[ Banging , electricity crackles ]
[ Audience screaming ]
[ Banging ]
♪
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Crying ]
♪
[ Screams ]
[ Chair thuds , audience screams ]
[ Normal voice ] Oh , my God . I 'm so sorry .
No , no , no , no . No , I 'm sorry . I 'm so sorry .
I never should have put you in that position . Okay ?
[ Whispering indistinctly ]
You 're okay . You 're okay . Just breathe .
That was ...
You 're okay .
Ladies and gentlemen ,
have you ever seen anything like that ?
This is unconscionable , Jack .
I would like to point out
a number of tricks employed by the so-called doctor .
And you 'll get your turn , Car .
Right now ...
some messages .
[ Mid-tempo music plays , applause ]
♪
[ Music ends ]
We 're clear . [ Bell rings ]
Is this a talk show or a fucking freak show ? !
I mean , the depths you people have sunk to .
Carmichael , just take it easy , okay ?
Let 's get Sammy in to mop that brow of yours .
Sammy ?
Lilly , are you okay ?
A bit embarrassed , I guess . I 'm okay .
Phil . I 'm sorry . Can we get a hand with these straps ?
- I got you . - June .
Come here . Come here .
Just , let 's ...
You 're okay . [ Restraints clicking ]
Jesus . That was ... I mean ...
[ Gasps ]
I knew that we were gonna see something amazing tonight ,
but ...
we got to get you guys back on as soon as possible .
This could become , like , a regular spot .
The tall trees .
What did she mean by that ?
I don 't know . You tell me .
This isn 't some kind of parlor trick , Jack .
I know that , June . I mean , this ...
There is something very special happening here with Lilly .
With you .
I just ... I want to be a part of it .
- Uh ! You 're hurting me ! - Sorry , kid .
- Look , I 'm trying here . - Hey , Phil .
It 's okay , it 's okay . I got this .
Can I see that ? Thanks . Thanks , guys .
Go ahead .
It 's okay , Lilly . It 's okay .
- Thank you , Jack . - Mm-hmm .
No , she 's great . She 's got it all .
Well , this is all very exciting . Thank you so much .
- Sorry . - Send regards to Bonnie
- and the kids . Okay . Bye-bye . - We 'll have you back next year .
This isn 't about ratings anymore , Leo . This is sorcery .
Listen to me , you goddamn shit-your-pants Mick asshole !
Dial up that grin . Dial it up .
Dial it up and get on with your job .
And not one more word .
[ Woman singing scales ]
♪
It 's all smoke and mirrors , Gus . Trust me .
Leo should have cut the whole show right after Christou died .
Bombed , you mean ?
No . Didn 't you hear ?
He 's dead .
Puked his guts out on the way to Sinai .
Two minutes , everyone .
We 're on the homestretch . Let 's keep it going .
- [ Grunts ] - Thank you , Jack .
Yeah . Come here .
And what are we doing now , Jack ?
Um , now it 's nearly time to say good night , darling .
- [ Sighs ] Oh . - Jack .
Sammy . Checks on June and Lilly .
Okay , so three of the crew have just walked off ,
the Communications Commission
have called an emergency meeting at 7 : 00 a.m. , and ...
- Bedford . - Mm-hmm .
What did he say ?
Just that he thinks it 's the biggest TV event
since the moon landing .
- Who was I to disagree ? - We 're back !
Baby ! Back ! We 're back from the fucking dead !
We 're talking about 35 , maybe even 40 share .
" The night Jack Delroy interviewed
- that cock-fucking devil " ! - Well , it might not
be the headline The Times , run with , or The Post ,
for that matter , but something in that vein .
Oh , and Bedford also took quite a liking
to ... to June , too .
- Asked when she 'd be back . - I 'll do what I can .
I guess I don 't have to kiss Cavendish 's ass .
Cavendish ? Screw Cavendish .
After tonight , every fucking Fortune 500 will be lining up
to be a part of the resurrection of Jack Delroy .
If anyone 's gonna be kissing ass , it 's them .
What 's the matter ?
Just [ Sighs ]
That girl 's voice ...
I know . How did she do that ?
Yeah , but at the end , I mean , she sounded just like Minnie .
- You heard that . - No , no , no , no .
Don 't ... Don 't you go all screwy on me , Jack .
I 've already got Gus back there prepping for an exorcism .
I just got spooked . That 's all .
Let me tell you something .
If Minnie were here , she 'd be saying ,
" You get out there , Mr. Midnight ,
and you knock ' em dead . "
Positions , people . 10 seconds .
We 'll drop the costume parade to give Carmichael
a few more minutes on his soapbox ,
and then we 'll wrap it up , throw it to Cleo .
10 seconds , people .
- Jack . - Can we have Cleo standing by ?
Dagger . [ Bell rings ]
And in five ...
four ...
[ Up-tempo music plays , cheers and applause ]
♪
[ Music ends ]
Welcome back .
Ladies and gentlemen ,
before we continue , I 'd like to apologize to anyone
who may have been upset or offended
by what you saw before the break .
It 's not every day that you see a demonic possession
on live television .
Lilly ...
can you assure everyone that you 're okay ?
Yes . I 'm fine , Jack .
And do you have any recollection
of what just happened ?
It 's hard to explain .
It 's like I 'm asleep , but I 'm awake at the same time .
I just try to focus on June 's voice .
I 'm sorry if Mr. Wriggles said anything rude .
Alright , enough with all this subterfuge .
- May I , Jack ? - Yeah . Oh , please .
Because , you know , I 'm dying to hear you explain away
what we all just witnessed here . Let 's hear it .
Let me preface this by saying
that my chief concern is the welfare ,
indeed the sanity , of this young girl .
- How dare you ? - I beg your pardon ?
[ Scoffs ]
[ Audience murmuring ]
Before I became her guardian ,
Lilly lived in the cruelest conditions imaginable .
I studied her , yes . I treated her .
But I also gave her two things
I 'm sure you 're just as skeptical of ...
love and compassion .
Lilly and I are family .
I can assure you all there is no demon
lurking inside this child .
Clearly , she has been placed in a hypnotic state ,
then manipulated by the good doctor
- to perform her bit . - Hypnosis ?
Then ... Then how do you explain the physical transformations
with her skin ? The voice changed .
There was banging on the walls of the studio .
- She levitated , for God 's sakes ! - Granted ,
the stagecraft was impeccable .
[ Audience booing ]
- Do you know what I think , Car ? - Pray tell .
I think that you are just a self-righteous ,
coldhearted curmudgeon who 's trying to weasel
his way out of parting with half a million bucks .
- Yeah ! - Yeah !
[ Applause ]
If you 'll allow me , Jack ,
I 'd like to prove my thesis beyond a shadow of doubt .
Be my guest .
- I 'll need a volunteer . - [ Laughs ]
- Thank you , Gus . - Hmm ?
[ Laughter ]
Yes , if you 'll join me center stage .
Could I have those chairs back here , please ?
Do as you 're told , Gus . Gus .
[ Cheers and applause ]
Car . You 've got five minutes . Make ' em count .
Don 't worry , Jack . What I have in store
should provide a very fitting climax to your show .
My wife likes the way
my head sits on my shoulders , Mr. Haig .
I hope you 're not planning to , uh ...
Make it spin ?
Oh , I plan to make everybody 's head spin .
[ Audience " oohs " ]
[ Breathes deeply ]
Could I just have the lights dimmed , please ?
[ Switch clicks ]
[ Chuckles ]
A bit of atmosphere never hurt , did it , Dr. June ?
You know what we say in TV land ...
Where there 's smoke , there 's probably a smoke machine .
[ Laughter ]
My compliments to the producer .
Okay , Gus .
[ Breathes deeply ]
Are we feeling comfortable ?
Sure .
I hope everyone here in the studio
and you at home are all feeling comfortable , too .
It 's important that everyone is as relaxed as they can be .
Now , I have something here
that I want you all to look at .
Do you think we might be able to get a close-up ?
Mm .
[ Watch ticking ]
I will now ask you all to stare into my watch .
Even you , Jack .
Got a good shot on all the studio monitors here .
I hope our viewers at home are also paying attention .
Watch carefully .
' Round ...
and ' round , it goes .
Is everyone feeling nice and relaxed ?
♪
[ Button clicks ]
Good .
- Now , Gus ... - Hmm ?
... tell me all about this vermiphobia of yours .
I 'm sorry . My what ?
Your morbid fear of worms .
How do you know about that ?
What is it about them that so unsettles you ?
Isn 't it obvious ? They 're such ugly , slimy things .
No arms , no legs , no eyes .
Indeed . Quite grotesque .
And they seem to thrive wherever it 's dark and moist ...
the soil , the mud , the human body , even .
Disgusting .
Do you realize that you are now deep in a trance ?
No , sir , I do not .
A very ... deep ...
trance .
Okey-dokey . You 're the expert . [ Chuckles ]
And when I click my fingers ,
you will be entirely under my command .
Look , this is silly . I don 't think it ...
[ Snaps fingers ]
Gus , can you hear me ?
Yes .
Do you know where you are ?
Here ...
in the studio with you .
You don 't feel any different ?
No .
Why should I ?
[ Moaning ]
What is that ? Do you hear that ?
♪
Geez , it 's ...
It 's hot in here .
♪
Skin 's itchy .
You alright , Gus ?
Yeah . Just , uh , so damn itchy .
[ Chuckles ]
Your neck .
It 's bleeding .
I did nick myself shaving earlier .
Geez .
[ Audience screaming ]
What is that ?
[ Audience " ohhs " ]
Jesus !
Now , just stay calm , Gus .
No . No ! I can feel them .
They 're inside me .
Jesus !
Aaaahhh !
Aah ! [ Lilly laughs ]
♪
[ Audience gasps , screams ]
Oh , God !
[ Snaps fingers ]
Help me , Car .
Oh , God !
Oh , Jesus Christ !
[ Lilly laughing ]
Why is Gus acting so silly ?
[ Audience screaming ]
[ Choking ]
This wasn 't meant to happen .
[ Audience screams ]
[ Worm squeaking ]
[ Jack gasping ]
Uhh !
Dreamer , here !
Awake !
- How do you feel , Gus ? - Fine .
Uh , when do we begin ? [ Switch clicks ]
- Oh ! - Geez ! When did that happen ?
[ Laughter ]
Geez .
You mean you have no idea ? There were worms all over you .
Worms ?
Oh , God , I hope not . I hate worms .
[ Laughter ]
Okay , Car .
What the hell just happened ?
I did the exact same thing June did ,
just with a tad more imagination .
You said I used to be the best . Perhaps I still am .
Now would be the appropriate time to applaud .
[ Scattered applause ]
Mm . [ Chuckles ]
You 're saying you just hypnotized all of us ?
I 'm pretty sure I had most of you here in the studio ,
and no doubt a number of our viewers at home .
Fortunately , you 're a suggestible lot .
What 's he talking about , June ?
He played a mean trick on us , that 's all .
Leo , um , can you get the guys up in videotape
to play back that last bit ?
Yep . Lining it up .
Now , if Carmichael 's right ... if ... then ...
oh , boy . We 're in store for some very interesting viewing .
Bravo . Yes , let 's do that .
Best idea you 've had all night , Jack .
They 're cueing it up now . Let 's start there .
You don 't feel any different ?
No .
Why should I ?
Because something dreadful is about to happen .
It 's dawning on you . Hear that ?
Ghostly sounds , anguished moaning from beyond .
That is not the way I remember it .
You 're hot . You 're itchy .
Feels like something 's crawling under your skin .
It 's hot in here .
[ Laughter ]
Skin 's getting itchy .
Your neck . It 's bleeding .
I did cut myself shaving earlier .
- What ? ! - What ? !
[ Audience murmuring ]
- What is that ? - Worms .
Jesus Christ !
That 's right . Worms . Dozens of them .
Hundreds of them . Now , just stay calm , Gus .
No ! They 're inside of me . I can feel ' em !
Show me .
- Get ' em out ! - They are coming out .
Oh , boy . Okay , let 's stop there .
[ Laughter , scattered applause ]
I 've never been so embarrassed in my whole life .
[ Audience " aws " ]
Is there ...
anyone who did not see the worms the first time around ?
I didn 't see them .
- One . - I didn 't see them .
You did ? Okay . So aside from a couple
of people in the audience ,
uh , it looks like you
have made fools of us all once again , Car .
All in a day 's work .
I did not hypnotize Lilly ,
or the studio audience ,
- or the viewers at home . - Oh , come on , Doctor .
You 've been caught dead to rights .
At least America can sleep a little easier
knowing the devil 's not going to pop out of their TV screens .
If Mr. Haig thinks we 're playing a trick on everyone ,
then maybe we should look back
at that part of the show , too , Jack .
- Yeah . - Yeah .
Do you mean when Mr. Wriggles joined us ?
Mm-hmm .
You don 't think the television cameras lie ,
do you , Mr. Haig ?
- No , of course not . - Jack , please .
Lilly has been through enough . No .
Okay , folks . I 'm sorry .
Our producers are telling me that the lovely Miss Cleo James
is standing by to take us out .
And ...
I ...
I just think maybe we should bring her back at a later date ,
because we can 't leave everybody hanging like this .
- Yeah ! - Yeah !
I 'm sorry . We can no longer take any part in any of this .
Lilly , we 're leaving .
But we want everyone to know the truth .
- Don 't we , June ? - Yeah !
- Standing by , Jack . - We 're staying .
- Please . - We could start it .
Yeah . Right there . [ Click ]
It 's gonna be okay .
Speak .
[ Demonic voice ] You know who I am , Doctor .
[ Audience gasps , screams ]
- Quiet . - You say cameras
- don 't lie , right , Car ? - Who are these people ?
What is this ?
There must be some rational explanation .
My IFSIP team may need to take these tapes in
for forensic examination .
My purpose ?
Good to see you again , Jack .
Sorry . I don 't believe we 've been acquainted .
- Don 't be a fool . - Did you see that ?
- We go way back . - I 'm sorry . Can you stop it ?
Just go back a few seconds .
[ Tape rewinding ]
Stop .
Okay .
Go from there , but very slow , please .
[ Distorted ] Good to see you again , Jack .
Slower .
[ Distorted ] Sorry . I don 't believe we 've been ...
Okay . Freeze it there .
That 's just a glitch , Jack .
No , it 's something else . Now go one frame at a time .
No , no . Sl ... Can you slow it down ?
Keep going .
[ Hisses ]
Minnie ?
[ Audience gasping ]
My God ! [ Lilly crying ]
It is you .
You set the whole thing up .
Did you really think another special appearance
from Madeleine might actually save your little gabfest ?
- You 're okay . - No , no , no , no , no , no , no .
This ... This makes perfect sense .
You ... You conspire with Christou
to have him reach your dead wife ,
throw in a few Grand Guignol theatrics with these two ,
and then top it all off
with some clever videotape manipulation .
It 's genius , Jack .
Cynical , depraved genius .
[ Electricity crackling ]
Ladies , the encore is quite unnecessary !
[ Audience murmuring ]
Um ...
[ Crackling continues ]
Can we get some help here ?
Now !
[ Electricity crackling ]
[ Audience gasping ]
♪
[ Crackling continues ]
Uh ! Aah !
[ Screams ]
Cut the show , Leo ! Cut it !
[ Lilly screams ]
♪
[ Audience screaming ]
The power of Christ compels you !
The power of Christ ...
[ Crack ]
[ Audience screaming ]
Gus !
Lilly , to me !
[ Choking ]
♪
Aah !
[ Choking ]
Lord of Flies , God of Ungodliness ,
I solemnly promise to worship and obey thee
and perform thy unholy bidding .
♪
Oh , fuck .
[ Breathing heavily ]
♪
[ Demonic voice ] Abracadabra .
[ Screaming ]
♪
Everybody , get out !
Jack ! Jack ! Come on !
Come on . Please . Please .
♪
[ Static hissing ]
[ Feedback whining ]
[ Mellow music plays ]
♪
But now here 's Mr. Midnight ...
Jack Delroy !
[ Cheers and applause ]
- Jack ! Jack ! - Whoo-hoo-hoo !
Jack !
Come on in , Jack .
[ Cheers and applause continues ]
We love you , Jack !
[ Gus laughs ]
[ Woman chanting " Jack ! " ]
How did I get here ?
The same way you always get here , Jack ...
straight down 5th and right on 47th .
[ Laughter ]
♪
[ Laughter continues ]
You okay , Jack ? [ Laughs ]
[ Laughter ]
♪
[ Laughter stops ]
[ Ominous music plays ]
♪
I am sick of it , Crog !
Stuck in the cave all day cooking your saber-tooth stew
while you and your troglodyte buddies
go out hunting all day long .
[ Laughter ]
♪
[ Applause ]
What the fuck is going on ?
[ Audience " oohs " ]
Don 't think that 's the line we rehearsed . [ Laughs ]
Leo ! [ Applause ]
Oh , where are you going , Jack ?
Jack , we 're still on air . Jack ?
Now , I 've brought something really special
for you today , Jack .
Here she is .
I 'll just get her out so you can have a really good look .
- [ Worm shrieking ] - [ Gasps ]
Hello !
- Jesus . - Here she is .
- [ Audience " awws " ] - Relax .
- Jack , she 's perfectly harmless . - No .
[ Worm hisses , shrieks ]
Jack and I first met when I was doing " Oh ! Calcutta ! "
at the Eden .
[ Gasps ]
My , you should have seen him blush
when he came backstage and was confronted
with all those glorious naked bodies .
[ Jack breathing shakily ]
Remember , darling ?
No .
Is that another thing you 've managed to forget ?
You 're dead .
[ Inhales deeply ]
[ Mellow music plays ]
[ Distorted music plays ]
♪
Okay , Penelope .
Now give the Wheel of Wonder a big spin .
Just remember to let go .
Last week we had a lady go ' round for hours and hours .
Spin the wheel !
[ Up-tempo music plays , rhythmic clapping ]
Switch off your televisions . [ Gus laughs ]
Turn off your TV sets .
Stop watching this .
Turn it off !
[ Tempo increases ]
Stop !
Please .
♪
Aah !
Stop it !
[ Camera shutters clicking ]
[ Indistinct shouting in distance ]
- Welcome to the family , Jack . - Over here !
Jack , Jack . Congratulations on your ratings win .
What did you have to sacrifice to get here tonight ?
Oh , Jack Delroy 's greatest sacrifice is yet to come .
[ Bell ringing ]
♪
Hm .
Great show tonight , Jack .
At least a 40 share .
Maybe even a 50 .
Come .
♪
[ Whimpers ]
Now drink up , Jack .
[ Group shrieking ]
♪
[ Gulping ]
[ Coughs ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
♪
[ Woman vocalizing ]
[ Respirator hissing ]
♪
There you are .
I was worried they wouldn 't let you see me .
♪
They told you you could have it all .
Didn 't they ?
Be number one ?
Well , you finally made it , darling .
But you had to pay a price .
Exit Minnie , stage left .
I never thought that they 'd ...
Your soul belonged to them .
Still does .
[ Gasping ]
It wasn 't supposed to turn out this way .
You have to believe me .
You 're on your own now , Jack .
I love you .
[ Sobs ] I love you , Minnie .
[ Crying ]
[ Voice breaking ] Then , please ...
do this one last thing for me .
♪
[ Gasps , groans ]
The pain . Please .
Please . You know what to do .
Please .
- [ Groans ] - Oh .
[ Breathes sharply ]
Do it . Do it .
[ Gasps ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
♪
Yes .
[ Screams ]
♪
[ Gasps ]
Dreamer , here . Awake .
[ Sirens wailing in distance ]
Dream , here . Awake .
Dream , here .
[ Sustained beep ]
[ Static hissing ]
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
♪
♪ Write another song for the money ♪
♪ Something they can sing , not so funny ♪
♪ Money in the bank to keep us warm ♪
♪ Roll another joint for the Gipper ♪
♪ Get the Gipper high , he gets hipper ♪
♪ Stick it in his mouth and keep him warm ♪
♪ Elect another jerk to the White House ♪
♪ Gracie Slick is losing her dormouse ♪
♪ Take her off the streets and keep warm ♪
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
♪
[ Woman vocalizing ]